[♪ opening theme song playing]
[wings fluttering]
[YURU] I still remember
the first time
I sensed another person's
bloodlust.
It happened shortly before
my parents left the village.
He must've been a bandit.
My dad took me
deep in the mountains to hunt.
But the one being hunted was me.
"A child like you
isn't needed in this world."
That's what I felt from him.
-[Yuru (child) gasps]
-[stabbing]
[YURU]
I could feel the hostility
through every pore
on my body.
-[Yuru (child) whimpers]
- [YURU] Under my skin,
stabbing straight
through my flesh
and into my guts.
[Yuru (child) breathing heavily]
[MINE] Yuru! [grunts]
I'm here!
Look at me!
Did he hurt you?
No.
It's his blood.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have
taken my eyes off you.
[YURU (CHILD)]
Daddy, what is this feeling?
My boy, remember it well.
This is bloodlust.
You may experience it again. No.
It will happen.
Time after time,
as long as you live.
Any time you feel it,
do not hesitate to do
what needs to be done.
[Yuru (child)
continues whimpering]
[thudding]
[panting]
[footsteps]
[MINE] It looks like
you're a bit calmer now.
Good.
We'll spend the night
on the mountain
and return
to the village tomorrow.
That should give you time
to collect yourself.
-Take a deep breath in...
-[Yuru (child) inhales]
-...and let it out, slow.
-[Yuru (child) exhales]
[MINE] That's it.
Release your breath,
and with it, all the noise
inside of your mind.
-Don't let fear win.
-[breathes deeply]
A distracted mind
leads to a swift end.
Know that on the hunt,
there are lives on the line.
Not only that of our quarry,
but ours as well.
Stay calm and assess
your surroundings.
Think about what you need to do.
Consider what tools you have
on hand, in the moment.
That's how you'll survive.
-[Yuru (child) exhales]
-[MINE] Remember,
death strikes where our fears
make us vulnerable.
[fire crackling]
[MINE] Listen, Yuru.
Don't tell anyone
in the village
that you were
attacked by a bandit.
But why not?
What if all his allies
are lying in wait,
preparing for another attack?
Don't we have to warn
everyone else?
No. I'm confident
they won't attack our village.
[YURU (CHILD)] Huh?
Do not say a word.
When we get back home,
I want you to stay calm
and act like normal.
Pretend nothing happened
out here.
[Yuru (child) grunts]
[MINE] I promise, you can do it.
[bird cawing]
[MAN] Hey, Mine!
[MINE] Good morning.
Glad you're well.
We heard you hadn't
returned last night.
We could hardly sleep
out of worry.
[MINE] Sorry about that.
We wound up chasing our target
too deep into the mountains.
Had to think
of my little one's stamina,
so we decided to play it safe.
You camped out overnight
and still came back
empty-handed?
That's pretty unusual for you.
[Mine laughs]
Happens to the best of us.
[footsteps]
[KYOKA] There you are! Oh.
Oh, Kyoka! We're home.
Thank the gods.
And Yuru's with you.
[YAMAHA] We didn't know
what to think
when you didn't
come back last night.
Did something happen to you
in the mountains?
Nothing serious.
We let our quarry
get away from us, is all.
Are you hurt, child?
[Yuru (child) gasps]
[MINE] Hmm?
That's the blood
of a rodent we ate.
Boy, I'm hungry.
One rat wasn't nearly enough
for us, eh, son?
Where's Nagisa?
With Asa?
Yes. She's inside.
Well, all right.
Let's have breakfast together
with the girls, son.
[YURU (CHILD)] Sure.
♪
-[MINE] Nagisa.
-[Nagisa gasps]
Hi, Mom. We're both back!
[NAGISA] Welcome home.
You had me worried sick
last night.
Sorry, dear.
Sorry to you, too.
We were fairly far,
so it felt safer
to wait till sunrise.
You weren't hurt, were you?
Tell me you're all right, Yuru!
Nothing happened.
Please don't worry about me.
Man, I was so nervous out there,
I could barely get any sleep!
Must still be a little worn out.
[ASA (CHILD)] Listen...
[YURU (CHILD)] Huh?
Brother, take care of yourself.
[Yuru (child) chuckles softly]
[Asa (child) chuckles softly]
[Nagisa chuckles softly]
[Yuru (child) laughs]
You should've seen this thing.
It was monstrous!
-[MINE] Nagisa.
-[NAGISA] Hm?
[ASA (CHILD)] I'm sure you'll
get it next time you go out!
[Yuru (child) laughs]
You bet I will!
-[gasps]
-[ASA (CHILD)] Yeah, and then
-we can have a feast! [laughs]
-[Yuru laughs]
[YURU] Everything changed
for us that day.
Soon after,
Mom and Dad left the village
without me or Asa.
Or so I thought.
It seemed
only I was left behind.
When they fled the village,
they had a basket
containing the real Asa.
The girl I lived
the next ten years with,
the girl I believed
to be my sister
was nothing but a fake.
For those ten years,
the people of Higashi lied to me
through their teeth.
Or at least that's what
this supposed "real" Asa said.
But that wasn't
what hit me the hardest.
[ASA] The truth is, I died once.
One of Higashi's assassins
killed me.
[Yuru breathes shakily]
[ASA] We fled the village
in a rush.
People were after us
and the Kagemoris took us in.
After that,
things seemed better.
That is, until Mom and Dad
went missing.
Last year, when I was fifteen,
I was captured by assassins.
On that day, they took my life
and I gained the power of Break.
There, as I lay dead,
I saw the boundary
to what comes after
and came upon a daemon.
Half of a pair.
The one with the power of Break.
[BREAK]
Lo! New flesh has arrived!
[Asa gasps softly]
What's this?
Wait.
What happened when I was cut
by that Higashi assassin?
-[BREAK] You died.
-[Asa gasps]
[BREAK] For the first time,
you are dead.
[ASA] Then is this hell?
[BREAK] Well, it is no paradise
by looks, I'll grant you that.
Wait. You assumed
you'd been sent straight to hell
now that you've been killed?
Pray tell,
what have you done
that warrants
such self-loathing?
What kind of life
must you have had
in the land of the living?
You stand now at the boundary
betwixt your world
and where the dead rest eternal.
[wind blows]
[BREAK] Oh, come on.
Where'd I leave
the darned thing?
Ah!
[Break grunts]
There. This is it.
This is its name in the tongue
of your motherland.
Yomotsu Hirasaka.
It's like that story
my dad used to tell me.
The village legend.
"The day of the equinox,
a twin boy and girl is born
on either side of the sunrise,
splitting night and day.
They will cross over
to the shadow realm
and learn to command
the daemons."
[BREAK] It would seem
word of mouth
has twisted
the telling over time.
More accurately, it's
"just before the shadow realm."
Those people were from Higashi.
The place I once called home
tried to kill me.
[BREAK] None arrive here
without succumbing to death.
So? What will you do?
[ASA] Huh?
[BREAK] Those who come here
have two paths
they must choose from.
Embrace death or embrace me.
If you wish to die,
simply take a step off the path.
If you wish to live, accept me,
the power of Break,
and return from whence you came.
I'm quite useful!
Soon as they should
enter your sight,
you may part
an enemy commander's head
from their body
right on the battlefield.
You will be host unto power
enough to end wars by yourself.
Depending on the age,
you may be heralded a hero.
Break is bound by naught
but your own imagination.
In exchange,
you will be set upon by those
who wish to make use of you.
You may find yourself living
in the hell you feared.
You may curse your former self
for not accepting death.
[ASA] I believe hell found me
a while ago.
My mom and dad
both went missing.
I have no idea
what happened to them.
And it's all my fault.
Because I was born, they...
[Asa sniffles, gasps]
Hold on! What about my brother?
Has he come through here?
Was he killed?
[BREAK] I know not.
In the event of his death,
he would find himself
in Seal's domain.
He has not been here.
I do not know what's happened
to your brother,
-nor could I find out for you.
-[Asa gasps softly]
[Asa grunts, sighs]
[ASA]
Then what choice do I have?
We left him
by himself in the village.
I don't know
if he's still alive.
Maybe they killed him,
just like me.
But I have to try and save him!
[breathes shakily]
I can't just roll over
and die yet!
[BREAK] What will you choose?
To embrace life or death?
[Asa grunts softly]
[BREAK] You have
the most beautiful eyes.
Turn them upon the path ahead.
Never look back.
[man breathes heavily]
Hey. She isn't waking up!
No way.
They were the first
in four hundred years.
This was our chance!
Maybe this was a decoy
prepared by the Kagemori clan
to trick us!
I know this is the girl
I saw in the village.
There's no doubt about it!
[MAN] Yeah, I'm sure.
Years ago, when she was
just a little kid!
And they kept her in a cell
without proper lighting!
There is no way
you got a good look at her!
I know what I saw!
Then we screwed up,
'cause she ain't comin' back!
No one's getting
the power of Break!
Don't forget, the boy
is still with the village!
Seal is more than strong enough
to control the underworld!
The kid's ours!
He's totally brainwashed.
He'll make
an obedient Seal user for us!
All we have to do
is kill him, and...
[both gasp]
[Asa grunts]
[Gabriel grunting]
You tracked her down?
-[Gabriel grunting]
-[GABBY] Show me!
[running footsteps]
[GABBY] Asa! [panting]
Asa!
[Gabby panting]
[GABBY] Asa. You dummy.
They're dead.
You're supposed to leave
all the murder
and mayhem to us lowlifes.
[ASA] Sorry, Gabby.
If I had any choice,
I wouldn't be a twin
fated to fulfill some prophecy.
But now, I can choose.
And I'll get my own hands dirty.
I'm sorry, Yuru.
You said you were looking
for the innocent little sister
you knew.
I'm afraid
you'll never find her.
No.
She died that day.
So they were an ox and a horse?
Like Ox-Head and Horse-Face?
They look old, but they're
still in great shape.
Seems like someone
really loved these little guys.
[mud scraping]
[Gabby groans]
Man, I'm starving.
Wonder what we're having
for breakfast.
-[Gabriel grunts]
-[birds chirping]
[DERA] Good morning, everyone!
Is anybody in there?
Hey, wakey-wakey,
Kagemori clan!
Wait. Is this a call button?
Aren't rich people supposed
to have guards at the gate?
Uh, who are you?
Huh? Finally.
So, you must be
one of the Kagemori!
Sorry for bothering you
first thing.
My name is Ryu Tadera.
I believe you've got Yuru?
[JIN] The Tadera's here?
[YURU] Uh, Dera?
Mr. Big Brother
has quite the ride home.
I'd completely forgotten
about Dera!
[JIN] What shall we do?
Oh, uh...
We did forget to tell him
we left, huh?
So, yes.
I trust them with my life.
They're a huge pain in the ass.
You don't wanna get involved
with guys like that
if you don't have to.
[YURU] I kinda wanna hear
both sides of the argument
at the same time.
[Yuru grunts]
Very well.
Would you mind asking Dera
to come over here?
I'll let them know.
Akio, escort him
to the front door.
[AKIO] Sir.
No murder this time.
[AKIO] Of course, sir.
I said I'm sorry.
[ASUMA] Good day, Jin.
The manor is a bit of a mess.
Did something untoward happen?
Morning, Asuma. Nice to see you.
We had a number of external
Daemon Wielders who broke in.
They tore the entire place up.
[ASUMA] Oh, my!
Sounds like a tough night!
And yet you didn't come to help.
Care to explain?
What were you up to?
Just sleeping.
Didn't notice the commotion
with your supposedly
"excellent hearing?"
[HAGURE] Whoa! This is terrible!
What is all this, Jin?
[ASUMA] Ah, Hagure. Morning!
[HAGURE] Ah.
Good morning, Asuma.
Do you know what I missed?
Was there an earthquake?
Apparently, there was a raid!
A number of Daemon Wielders
targeting Asa and her brother
attacked the manor.
[gasps] Is Asa okay?
Truly sorry
for making you worry!
I'm fine.
[sighs] Scared me.
Wait.
They were after her
and her brother?
Yes. We brought him here.
Oh, you were finally reunited!
At last! How nice. Huh.
Yuru, was it?
Our Asa here, she's told me
so much about you.
These are my brother's daemons,
Left and Right.
[HAGURE] Nice to meet you.
I feel terrible,
I couldn't help you
when you needed me, Jin.
I hit my deadline
and crashed hard.
[JIN] Not to worry.
Good job finishing your work.
But this just sucks.
We made the barrier
around the manor
specifically to stop this
from happening.
It does make you wonder
how they got in.
But rest assured,
we'll figure out
after we tort...
uh, interrogate our captives.
[HAGURE] Bummer, man.
Even our own mansion
isn't safe these days.
Gotta sleep with one eye open.
Hey, that's Dad's car.
The old man
finally made it back.
Welcome home, sir.
[GONZO] Yes.
Sounds like there was trouble
while I was out!
Salutations!
How is everyone today?
Master, is that...
The name's Ryu Tadera.
[GONZO]
We bumped into each other,
so I gave him a ride.
He's from the Tadera clan.
Seems he's
young Yuru's guardian.
-Holdin' up okay, kiddo?
-[Gonzo exclaims]
So you're the fabled Yuru!
Gonzo, head of this house.
Good to meet you!
And I've heard
of you two as well.
What wonderful daemons you have!
[laughs]
[JIN] The retainers
of Higashi Village, the Taderas.
They've acted as their
liaisons for generations.
Never once has someone
from our clan
seen one of them face-to-face.
They're famously cautious.
And now,
one wanders into our territory
completely defenseless?
Think the Kagemoris and Dera
are in league with each other?
Not a chance.
I can feel their
outright bloodlust from here.
The old man and Jin
want to kill Dera.
[RIGHT] What could the Taderas
have done to them
to deserve such hatred?
[YURU] Hey, Dera?
What's up?
[YURU] Heard a funny story.
This one told me about Seal.
She said I'll get the power
when I die.
But you already knew that,
yeah?
Same with these two,
but no one told me.
I heard some old legends
the village passed down,
but no details. So?
I've seen you're kind
and caring to a fault, kid.
What if someone
blackmails you with Asa?
You'd die for her
without blinking.
I don't want you thinkin'
you can throw your life away
'cause you got one do-over.
It's not that simple.
Get it out of your head.
There's no way for us
to guarantee
you would actually
come back to life.
If you will recall,
you were not the first twins
born of Higashi Village.
Merely the first
in four-hundred years.
One of the last twins
failed to revive upon death.
[Yuru gasps softly]
[Asa breathes shakily]
[Hagure gasps]
Well! Let's not get too heavy
while standing around like this!
So, boy, are you hungry?
[YURU] Uh...
Come to think, I haven't eaten
since last night.
All right! Why don't we have
this talk over breakfast?
It's my treat! Hey!
Tell the kitchen!
We're having guests!
[SERVANTS] Yes, sir.
And I promise,
no poison in yours!
[laughs]
Aw, thank you! Let's dig in.
[ASA] I get to have
breakfast with my brother!
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[HAGURE] I work as a mangaka.
I'm Hikaru Hagure!
[YURU] "Mangaka?"
What's that mean?
[GONZO] Each time
twins like you are born,
the world is thrown into chaos.